<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bytes &amp; Stuff</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bytes &amp; Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lost in Stone Town: A Midnight Adventure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/midnight-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/midnight-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lost-in-stone-town-a-midnight-adventure&#34;&gt;Lost in Stone Town: A Midnight Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Travelling has a way of humbling you; just when you think you’ve seen it all, a new city reminds you that you’re only scratching the surface. Earlier this year I set off for Zanzibar, a trip I had been looking forward to for ages. I imagined warm evenings, coastal breezes, and the gentle rhythm of island life. What I got on the first night was something closer to a crash course in survival travel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Habits, Hierarchies, and Rituals - The Real AI Challenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-blueberry-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ai-blueberry-muffin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The excitement around AI in software development is everywhere. Every week, new tools promise to boost productivity, accelerate delivery, and raise the quality bar. Yet in many organisations, the impact of AI has been underwhelming. Not because the technology isn’t powerful, but because old habits, entrenched bureaucracy, and ritualised ways of work are quietly holding teams back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s unpack this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;old-habits-result-in-retrofitting-instead-of-rethinking&#34;&gt;Old Habits Result in Retrofitting Instead of Rethinking&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Software delivery teams are creatures of habit. Developers, testers, analysts, and product owners have refined their methods over years, influenced by the prevailing wisdom of waterfall and agile. These practices have become a gospel called “the way things are done.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking in prompts: How AI is reshaping our minds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/thinking-in-prompts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/thinking-in-prompts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across a few pieces arguing that AI is eroding our ability to write, and along with it, our ability to think clearly. I get the point. If machines can write for us, then what happens to our own voice, our ability to wrestle with ideas, or even just put coherent thoughts together?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But here’s the twist: the way we use AI today, especially tools like ChatGPT, is primarily through writing. Not polished, publish-ready writing, but something far more subtle and surprisingly complex: the prompt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hello-and-welcome&#34;&gt;Hello and Welcome!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a space where I explore the ideas, experiences, and reflections that keep my mind engaged. From the latest in technology and the intricacies of leadership to the ever-evolving business landscape, the joys of travel, and the occasional musings — this blog is my way of making sense of it all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-to-expect&#34;&gt;What to Expect&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can expect rambles, thoughtful insights, practical takeaways, and the occasional deep dive into topics that connect technology and humanity, leadership and growth, or simply the wonders of the world. Whether you’re here for inspiration, knowledge, or just a new perspective, I hope you’ll find something that resonates with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
